I'm guessing if we had a defending the
kingdom straw poll for NFL executive of
the year every year, maybe we're biased,
he would be the general manager of the
Kansas City Chiefs, Brent V. We don't
know why you haven't got it before, but
anyway, that being said, we're here at
the NFL combine and just want to ask you
the value of this experience. Uh maybe
how it's changed, but when you go to the
combine, you're going here's what I want
to get out of this. What is that? Yeah,
I think what we really strive to get is
just um that in-depth knowledge of of
the person. I mean, you hear so much
about the player and our college scouts
do a great job of kind of painting the
picture, but having all those pieces
kind of fall into place and um you know,
the time that we get with these players
in the formal and and even the informal
interviews is extremely valuable to us.
um you can learn a lot and um it really
kind of reinforces some of the things
that um we had been told all season, but
there's also times where um things don't
quite work out that way and it it allows
us to do an even deeper dive on a
prospect. So, it's the first part of the
process, but it's a very valuable one.
You and your guys always attack this
time of year and the track record in the
draft kind of shows that, but is there
even more excitement this time
considering we're picking at nine? This
team hasn't picked in the top 10 in a
very long time and you have a chance to
get a really good player early on.
>> Yeah, I think certainly there is. I
mean, obviously the you don't ever want
to be picking that high, but um I think
we're in that situation, so we have to
make the most of it. And you know, we'll
have difficult decisions as we go. But,
you know, I'm not just focused on the
first round. I think the value of having
a top 10 pick in every round. You know,
I can't tell you how many times that,
you know, we finish day one and, you
know, we come back on day two and
there's six or seven guys that, you
know, in your mind they're never getting
to 32, but you're going to be right back
up the next day. um with it's funny
because our second round pick would be
kind of the talent level that we've been
picking for the first round in the last
10 years. So, I think coming into this
draft knowing that we should get at
least two of those guys and and then
just keep adding as uh the draft goes
on. So, it's a super um exciting
opportunity for us and we just have to
um be as prepared as possible and
capitalize and make the most of it.
>> Brad, I want to jump back. You talked
about the interviews, formal and
informal, but the landscape in which we
live now, the NIL landscape, the COVID
eligibility landscape. We got 26 year
old dudes here and we got 20-year-old
dudes here. How does that dynamic impact
in what you're trying to find out
intel-wise and guys that have been at
four schools in four years?
>> Yeah. Yeah. It certainly uh you know I
was saying that the podium today I think
that when we officially received
notification of of um underassman that
were returning to school I think we had
over 20 I think you know the number was
close to 25 players that we took out
from our top 100. So, that's a lot of
players and um it certainly impacts
uh the depth of the draft and you know,
in many ways the opportunity to get guys
that are still in that young
developmental stage and get them and and
kind of see it through. A lot of these
guys that you're drafting are kind of
reach maybe their, you know, athletic
ceiling. They're 24, as you mentioned,
Mitch, 24, 25 years old. So, it's it's
um it's another hurdle that we have to
overcome, but it's just it reemphasizes
the importance of of kind of tightening
that board up and and and finding the
top 100 guys uh right out of the gate
and then, you know, building your layers
on day three and and and and trying to
find those guys that are are talented,
that are driven, but do still have some
developmental upside. So, the athletic
testing gets a lot of the attention
around here, but like Mitch mentioned,
the interview process is super
important, whether it be the formal ones
or the informal ones. Uh, what do you
guys as a staff get out of the
interviews here in Indianapolis?
>> Yeah, I mean, just kind of how they're,
you know, you're going to get into a
little dive of of, you know, where
they're from and and their family, their
support system, which is is super
important, but really how these guys are
wired. um you know, not just how well
they love football, but what football
means to them. And I think that's that's
important because as you know, you know,
these guys have a chance to get paid
really well now in college and a lot of
these guys are coming in here um making
making I mean these quarterbacks are
making 89 million now. So um it's kind
of a trickle down effect. So, you know,
there most of the NIL is difficult for
us to navigate because it it keeps good
young players uh in college one year
longer and there's less younger players
with developmental upside. You know, the
one positive I think you can say is that
you get a picture of how these guys are
handling money and handling a certain
level of fame. And so, you know, you do
take what you can. And I think that
there's um an element of how these guys
have handled that. I mean, a lot of
these guys, I mean, some of these guys
have stayed in school and some of these
guys have done good with their money and
and um know how to handle it. And so,
you know, in some aspects, they're
they're a little bit more prepared for
for what they have um in front of them.
But um I think in just in general it you
know I I don't think the drafts until
there's a huge change or shift in the in
the way college runs. I think the drafts
will always um be leaner in regards to
you know draftable prospects and um just
means you have to do a little extra work
and and get that board dialed in just
right especially you know on day three
and day three as you know Mitch that's
our favorite day. I was going to say
that just leads right into my next
question because people zero in on nine,
but you're sitting at 40. You got three
of the top 75 picks, but how is how does
this several days at the combine impact
because you've crushed day two and day
three and considering the landscape
change, do you look at it differently?
And how do you get is it harder to get
to crush day three than it's been
before? uh it makes it more difficult
just from the the volume of players and
and a lot of those young guys that would
fill up your day three guys are are
staying in school. But the way I look at
day three in the draft is is unique. I
think like in the first round and really
the first 75 players I think across the
league most teams have almost the same
75 players. There's a little um degree
in differences, I'm sure, across the
board, but I mean, in general, if you
have a top 75, I mean, most of those
guys are kind of the same names and it's
just a a matter of strategically, you
know, placing value and fit and need and
all that kind of stuff, positional
value. But I think once you get to day
three, once you get like past pick 100,
like where where teams value guys in
four, five, six, and seven is extremely
different. I mean, I think you'll have a
lot of teams that value guys in the
round in rounds four or five and half
the league see them that way and half
the league think they're free agents and
you know, half of the guys that some of
these teams see as sixth, seventh round
value, the league sees as four or five
round value. So, I think there's just a
huge, you know, varying degree of of
where these prospects lie. And that's
why I think the first couple rounds are
always difficult because everyone's kind
of jocking for position for the same guy
potentially at the same positions and it
just cycles through for the first two
rounds into three. But once you hit
round four, then it's, you know, then it
really comes down to how much tape you
watched and and you know, how good your
evaluations are and the vision and the
scheme and the fit and and you know,
that's where I think the the extra work
that our our college guys do. And we
spend again just as much as time as um
on rounds five, six, and seven as we do
in one and two. And um and I think it
pays off more because I think leagues
don't see guys in the same value, you
know, conceptually. So, um, that's where
you got to be on your mark and that's
where you get the really good good
values.
>> Then you find Cooper McDonald who just
like
>> Yeah.
>> drives in.
>> With all that in mind, uh, tough
question to answer here. I don't want
you to give too much away, but if you're
looking at the draft from like a
thousand foot view, what are some of the
strengths of this draft in terms of
depth?
>> I think it's uh the defensive line I
think is is pretty solid through the
first three rounds. I think you're going
to have a lot of DNS um off the board
early. Um, so the Dline in particular,
the defensive end position, I think that
there's really good depth at the wide
out position and and some solid depth at
the the corner position. It's probably
leaner um at the running back position.
Um, but I we'll see. We'll see what
happens. Some years where, you know, you
thought that there was a lot of running
back depth, you didn't get one. And
maybe the year there was no depth, maybe
we'll we'll find a way to get one.
That's how it works out. But, um, it's
no different than every year. It always
rotates. But I think just um before we
get through the combine and the testing,
I just think right out of the gate,
defensive end is really deep and I think
that there's some solid depth at the
receiver position.
>> Final question, we appreciate your time.
>> Is the medicals and I'm going to go back
to the NIL. The fact that if when you
were coming out, I could call Delaware,
I could get your medical in Delaware,
you were there four years, five years.
Now, how much more of a challenge is it
to get a strong accurate medical on each
one of these players, especially the
ones like the corner from Tennessee who
did not play in 25?
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, that's other than
the the formal interviews, you can put
the medical right up there as the most
important aspect of this. So, our our
trainers come and our whole staff comes
in here and these guys go through the
whole the whole gamut now. I mean, they
go through all the the testings and the
M MRIs and imaging. So, that's the one
thing that we leave here feeling good
about. Um, a foundation of where these
guys are medically. I think the
secondary challenges are the guys that
we like that didn't get invited to the
combine. Those are typically the guys
that, you know, we're going to have to
bring in for 30. Um, you know, not
tipping our hand. On one end, obviously,
we like them, but on the other end,
there's a good chance that they didn't
go to the combine. If they don't go to
the combine, then we're we're just
looking at medical notes and and not
getting that hard driven data. So, um,
that's a little bit of a challenge, but
I think, you know, through the combine
and through these 30-day visits and then
you do get into a situation where if you
know there's a lot of guys that you
don't have medical on, sometimes you you
will work with other teams and exchange,
you know, not great notes or what your
value notes, but you'll exchange medical
notes for guys that say we brought in,
you know, of our 30 guys that we brought
in for an unofficial visit, we had 30
medical. If 10 of those guys were
combine guys, we didn't need the
medical. But the other 20, maybe 15, 20,
we'll get medical and then, you know, we
you only get 30. Um, so it wouldn't be
out of the question for me to call like
Borggoni and say, "Hey, I'll give you
five of my 30." I didn't go to the
combine for five years just to get the
medical. So that's a huge part of it.
And so the combine is huge because most
all the top prospects are here. So we'll
get that that medical data that we feel
good about moving forward.
>> Okay, it's time to get out your Invit We
Trust t-shirts and get them washed up
and ready. It's this time of year.